For this question, we need to determine if the given grammar generates
对于这个问题 我们需要确定给定语法是否
infinitely many strings starting from the nonterminal word.
从非终止字符开始产生无限多的字符串
So we can start from either substitution rule.
我们可以从任何一个替代规则开始
If we start from the first one, then we end up with 1 possible word.
如果从第一个开始 那么就以一个可能的词做结尾
If we start from the second word, then we get the letter a,
如果从第二个 Word 开始 然后得到字母 a
and then we can insert another word.
然后我们可以插入另一个 Word
This can be udacity, so then we end up with audacity.
这可以是 udacity 所以最后得到 audacity
We can do the same thing but twice.
我们可以做同样的事两次
So we have a, then instead of going to udacity, we do a again,
因此 我们有 a 然后不是 udacity 再做一次 a
and then we do udacity.
然后做 udacity
The way this is breaking down kind of looks like this.
这分解后看起来就像这样
It should be pretty clear that we can continue this forever and eventually end
这应该相当清楚 我们可以永远这样继续下去
with udacity.
最后以 udacity 结尾
So we can have an arbitrary number of a's, followed by udacity.
所以我们可以有任意数目的 a 后面跟着 udacity
This inidicates that this grammar generates an infinite number of possible words.
这表示说 这个语法产生了无限多可能的词语
In this grammar, we can see that every word begins with a root and then a tail.
在这个语法中 我们可以看到每个 Word 以字根 (Root) 起头 然后是字尾 (Tail)
So what we're going to do to see how many strings this generates is,
所以我们要做的是 看看这能产生多少字符串
go through every possible root there can be and then every tail there can be.
走遍每个可能的 Root 然后可能的 Tail
So root can be uda and also boda.
因此 Root 可以是 uda 和 boda
Tail can go directly to cious and city.
Tail 可以直接是 cious 和 city
But we should also look at this substitution rule that has root going directly to tail.
但我们也应该看看这个替换规则：Root 直接换成 Tail
So you could have a word that's really the same as tail tail,
所以你可能真的有这样的词 TailTail
which adds 2 more possible combinations to what root can be.
这多加了两个可能的组合到 Root
This gives us 4 possibilites for root and 2 possibilities for tail,
这给了四种 Root 与两种 Tail 的可能性
which means 8 possibilities all together.
这意味着总共有八种可能性
This grammar can generate 8 different words.
这个语法可以产生八种不同的词
We know that 8 < infinity, so this grammar does not generate an infinite number of words.
我们知道 8 小于无限 所以这个语法无法产生无限多的字词
So here we have a grammar that looks a lot like our first one.
我们在这里的语法 看起来很像第一个语法
However, let's still work it out to see if there's an infinite number of words.
无论如何 让我们把它做出来 看看是否有无限多的字词
So according to problem, we start with word.
根据问题 我们从 Word 开始
And there's only 1 substitution rule for word.
对 Word 只有一个替代规则
From pre udacious, we have 2 options.
从 pre udacious 我们有 2 个选项
We could go to super udacious, which gives us one complete word,
可以是 super udacious 给了我们一个完整的词
or we can do pre super udacious.
我们可以做 pre super udacious
You might have already noticed that we can keep substituting the pre with pre super,
你可能已经注意到 我们可以继续以 pre super 替代 pre
and we can keep doing this forever,
我们可以永远继续做下去
and stopping at any point and ending with some number of supers
在任何地方停下来 然后以一些 super 作结束
followed by udacious.
再跟着 udacious
This grammar generates an infinite number of strings.
这个语法产生了无限多的字符串